This is Imperial Military Command
with your 6:00 AM war update.
（ラジオ音声）帝国陸軍司令部
午前６時発表の戦局情報です
"Our forces, including our central unit,
are expanding in all theaters,"
我が軍は各方面および中央本隊の下
戦果を拡大中 北方ノルデン
says north Norden.
Next, a report by Western Command
for the Rhine front.
次 ライン戦線
西方方面軍司令部の報告
In response to a Republic night attack,
our forces launched a large-scale...
共和国の夜襲に対し
我が軍は大規模…
Unified Year 1924, Imperial Capital Berun
Hey, soldiers. Buy something
with your ration tickets.
（店員）
兵隊さん 軍用切符で買っとくれ
（兵士）配給で間に合ってるよ
We're already issued enough!
Johann's already defeated five people?
（女性）
ヨハン もう５人も倒したの？
Yes, he says he should
be back for Christmas.
（女性）うん クリスマスには
戻ってこれそうって
It's already been over six months
since I left the front lines.
（ターニャ）前線を離れ
既に半年以上が過ぎた
The stench of blood and gunpowder
has yet to disappear from my nostrils.
いまだ血と硝煙のにおいは
鼻の奥から消えないが―
But right now,
私は今…
喜々として学問に励んでいる
I'm enjoying my studies.
There's a sizable difference between
their education policies,
（ターニャ）教育方針に
相応の差異はあれど―
but a military university isn't that
different from a normal one.
軍大学も一般の大学と同じ
いや それ以上の待遇とも言える
No, in some ways, you're treated even better.
Part of it may be because I'm back from
the front lines with a medal on my chest.
前線帰りで勲章を
下げているせいもあってか―
こんな お子様の体でも
なじむのに苦労はない
But even in the body of a little child,
I've had no trouble fitting in.
All that's left is to use signaling theory
to show my human resources value,
あとはシグナリング理論に基づき
人的価値をアピールすれば―
and I'll be assured of an elite career track.
キャリアコースは確約され―
卒業後には
安全な後方勤務が待っている
And after graduation, I can live on
easy street in the rear echelons.
Everything's going my way.
これぞ順風満帆な人生だ
Episode Four
Campus Life
When units deviate from the mission plan,
（教官）
隷下部隊の逸脱行為に対し
士官の責任は
どう解釈されるべきかね？
should their commanding officer
be held personally culpable?
Victor.
（教官）ヴィクトール
（ヴィクトール）はっ！
Yes, sir! Even if he isn't directly involved,
he should accept moral responsibility—
直接 関与しておらずとも
道義的な責任は
引き受けるべきかと…
法律の話をしているのだぞ
この大バカ者！
I'm talking about the law, you idiot!
次！ デグレチャフ
Next! Degurechaff!
Yes, sir.
To clarify the question,
are there any senior officers present?
前提条件として 他の先任将校は
いらっしゃるのでしょうか？
We'll say there aren't.
（教官）いないものとする
A commander who's neglected his duty
to stop any such deviation
防止 鎮圧の義務を怠った指揮官は
作為義務違反に問われます
has failed in his legal duty.
Maximum penalty may include
the firing squad.
最高刑は 銃殺もありうるでしょう
うむ では先任将校がいた場合
And if there were a senior officer?
As long as the officer in question
has not done anything illegal,
当該将校による
不法行為がないかぎり
原則としては
指揮官に属する責かと
responsibility lies with
the senior officer, as a general rule.
ふむ よろしい
Very good.
What's the next course?
（学生）次の講義は？
（学生）
兵棋(へいぎ)演習だ 表の食堂行くか
Military spear practice.
Want to go to the cafeteria out front?
（学生）まだ早いだろう
It's still too early...
Degurechaff?
（ウーガ）デグレチャフ君
（ターニャ）ん？
Military Academy Student
Captain Maximilian Johann von Üger
Captain Üger?
ウーガ大尉殿
What is it?
何か？
Why are you always working on your rifle?
（ウーガ）
君は なぜいつもライフルを？
This equipment allows me to
fulfill my purpose at any time.
いついかなる時に 自分の存在意義を
賭すやもしれぬ装具であり
日ごろから備えておかねば
安堵(あんど)できないからです
I feel uneasy unless I make sure
it's ready at all times.
なるほど
前線帰りは違うな
I see.
People who return from
the front lines are different...
This is a matter of respect.
（ターニャ）
これは尊厳の問題であり―
敵の存在を再確認する必要行為だ
And a necessary act to reconfirm
my enemy's existence.
Who knows when I might have
a chance to shoot Being X?
あの存在Ｘ(エックス)を撃ち殺す好機が
いつ訪れるかもしれん
You should always be ready
to grab your chance.
好機への備えは
怠るべきではないし―
And I, personally, will never not be ready!
怠ることなど不可能！
Military Academy Library
（ターニャ）ふんっ ぬぬぬ…
Hannibal's Decisions at
the Battle of Cannae?
（ゼートゥーア）
「カンネーにおける
ハンニバルの決断」か
You're so studious.
勉強熱心なことだなあ
はっ！
し… 失礼しました 准将閣下
I-I'm sorry, General!
I'm Tanya Degurechaff, a student here.
自分は
ターニャ･デグレチャフ学生
帝国軍にて
魔導中尉を拝命しております
I'm a first lieutenant mage
in the Imperial Army.
Strategy and Operations
Vice Director Zettour.
参謀本部 戦務参謀次長の
ゼートゥーアだ
In a company, he'd be heading up business strategy!
（ターニャ）
戦務参謀といえば 後方のトップ！
企業なら 経営戦略の中枢！
In a company, he'd be heading up business strategy!
I'm honored to meet you!
お目にかかり 光栄であります！
I've heard a little about you.
（ゼートゥーア）貴官のことは
少しばかり耳にしている
You've been quite busy, I hear.
随分な活躍のようだ
Your words honor me, sir.
（ターニャ）はっ 過分な評価を
いただいております
If you aren't in a hurry,
could you come with me?
何か急ぎの用事がなければ
少しいいかね？
Yes, with pleasure!
はっ 喜んで！
This is the chance of a lifetime...
（ターニャ）
まさに千載一遇の好機！
図書館通いの かいがあったな
Worth spending all that time in the library.
Let's drink!
（男性）さあ 飲もうぜ！
（男性）かんぱ～い！
Cheers!
（男性）何度目だよ？
（男性たち）ハハハハ…
How many toasts so far?
Be seated.
（ゼートゥーア）掛けたまえ
（ターニャ）はっ 失礼します
Yes, sir. Excuse me.
Actually, I wanted to ask you something.
（ゼートゥーア）実は 貴官に
聞いてみたいことがあってな
What are your thoughts on the war?
（ゼートゥーア）
この戦争を どう見る？
Imperial soldiers are nearly
obsessed with precision.
（ターニャ）帝国軍人は正確さに
偏執的なまでに こだわる
Sir, I'm sorry,
but your question is too broad.
お言葉ですが 閣下のお言葉は
含意が広すぎます
（ゼートゥーア）
ハッ では言いかえよう
Let me change it, then.
貴官は この戦争の形態を
どう予想する？
What do you think the next
developments in the war will be?
I'm afraid I don't believe
I'm in a position to say.
（ターニャ）せん越ながら 自分は
言及すべき立場にないと思います
This isn't an inquiry.
（ゼートゥーア）
諮問しているわけではない
Give me your personal perspective.
主観でかまわん 自由に述べよ
Speak freely.
（ターニャ）これ以上の固辞は
失礼に当たるか…
I guess refusing any more would be rude...
では お言葉に甘えて
失礼いたします
Then, with your permission to speak freely.
この度の戦争は 大戦に
発展するものと確信いたします
I'm certain that this war
will grow into a world war.
（ゼートゥーア）大戦？
A world war?
A global war, involving the majority of
the world's most powerful countries.
列強の大半を巻き込んだ
世界規模での総力戦
世界大戦であります
That is a world war.
（ゼートゥーア）
ふむ その根拠は？
And what makes you think so?
The Empire is a relatively new addition
to the ranks of the world powers,
新興の列強たる帝国は
従来の列強と比較し
軍事的優位を誇っております
but it maintains military superiority.
Its military power is incredible.
その軍事力は絶大
１対１ならば
共和国にも勝利できるでしょう
In a one-on-one fight,
it could defeat the Republic.
If we do defeat the Republic
and restore peace,
共和国に勝利し
平和を回復しえた場合―
our country will be in a position of
absolute superiority on the continent.
我が国は大陸における
絶対的優位を確立します
However...
しかし… です
I don't think the other major powers,
そのような状況を 他の列強―
連合王国やルーシー連邦が
座視するとは考えられません
the Allied Kingdom and the Russy Federation,
will ever be willing to ignore that.
They're being forced to make a choice.
彼らは選択を迫られているのです
Will they allow a new ruling country's birth,
覇権国家の誕生を許容するか
拒絶するかの選択を…
or will they reject it?
Ah. I'm starting to see what you're saying.
なるほど 見えてきた
An intellectual conversation,
spent establishing a common understanding.
（ターニャ）共通認識を
確立しながらの知的な対話…
This is wonderful.
実に すばらしい
Thus, the interference of
other countries is inevitable.
故に 他国の干渉は必然です
共和国への借款から始まり―
It may begin with monetary
loans to the Republic
and eventually lead to the sharing
of weapons or volunteer forces.
武器供与や義勇兵派兵も
ありうるかと
An interesting opinion.
（ゼートゥーア）面白い意見だ
どう対処する？
How would you handle it?
I would try to start talks at an early stage.
早期の講和を模索しつつ
不可能ならば
消耗の抑制を第一にします
If that fails, I would focus on limiting
our own resource expenditure.
（ターニャ）
これぞ有意義なプレゼン
Now, this is how you give a presentation.
It's one of the best parts of being an adult.
社会人の醍醐味(だいごみ)だな
In other words,
（ゼートゥーア）つまりは…
（ターニャ）うん？
勝利を目指さないと？
you wouldn't try to win?
Crap!
（ターニャ）しまった！
大変マズい！ 実にマズい！
Not good!
Really not good!
うかつな口を撃ち抜きたい！
I want to shoot myself in my stupid mouth!
Th-That may be what I said,
こ… 言葉の上では
そのとおりですが
but by limiting our losses
while shedding enemy blood,
消耗を抑えながら
敵の血を流させることで―
いずれは帝国の勝利に至るかと
I believe the Empire would
win in the long run.
Do you have a practical plan?
具体案は あるのかね？
Cowards get the worst front-line jobs.
（ターニャ）
臆病者は前線で酷使される
I need to say something
as brave as possible!
ここは 少しでも勇ましいことを…
I would suggest a combination
歩兵による防御戦術と
魔導師による攻勢戦術の
組み合わせを提案いたします
of defensive infantry tactics and
offensive strategies with mages.
Mages are powerful,
but there aren't many of them.
魔導師は破壊力こそあれど
絶対数が少ない
They aren't good for capturing enemy bases.
拠点制圧に不向きだ
I agree.
肯定します ですが―
However,
mages excel in firepower and agility.
火力と俊敏性を誇る魔導師は
敵兵力を狩るのに理想的な兵科です
They're ideal for hunting enemy forces.
This is it! This is where I must
show my aggressiveness!
（ターニャ）ここだ！
ここで積極性を示すしかない！
Without national power and human resources,
no country can maintain a war.
（ターニャ）いかなる国も―
国力や人的資源が
払底してしまえば―
戦争を続けられません
In the sense that you win the battle
while limiting your losses,
自軍の損耗を抑制しつつ勝利する
という点をもって言うならば―
消耗抑制ドクトリンでしょうか
you could call it a loss-restriction doctrine.
I believe this may be the best use of mages.
魔導師の最適な運用形態かと
愚考いたします
ふむ 面白い
Interesting.
（ターニャ）乗り切ったあ～！
自分でも驚くほどの弁舌！
I made it through!
That speech even surprised me!
ハァ～ 戦後に備えて 法律関係の
資格を取るのも悪くないなあ…
Once the war ends, maybe I should go
for some kind of legal certification.
（ゼートゥーア）
で 実施に際してだが―
And?
If we wanted to put this into practice,
how large a force of mages
would you need?
魔導部隊は
どの程度の規模が必要だ？
だ… 大隊が適切でしょう
I... I believe a battalion
would be sufficient.
That would strain resources less
and meet the minimum for combat value.
兵站(へいたん)への負荷が少なく
かつ 戦力として最低限の単位です
If you wanted a trial run,
it would be the best option.
試験的に試すのならば最適かと
I see.
なるほど 検討しよう
I'll look into it.
正式な書面に まとめてくれたまえ
Put together a formal proposal.
R-Roger!
（ターニャ）
はっ 了解いたしました！
Excuse me!
失礼いたします
（レルゲン）
なっ… せ… “世界大戦”？
W-World war?
An all-out war involving the entire country?
“国家を挙げての総力戦”!?
The author's identity is confidential.
（ルーデルドルフ）
著者などは機密だが―
But this paper was given to me by Zettour.
ゼートゥーアから渡された論文だ
I'm sure you're busy inspecting
all the various theaters.
（ルーデルドルフ）各方面軍の
視察で忙しいだろうが―
But read it on the train or something.
移動中にでも目を通しておけ
（レルゲン）ハァ…
A war of madness, which expends human
lives as if they were just numbers...
（レルゲン）人命すら数字として
消費する狂気の戦争…
And it'll continue until
the country's collapse?
それが国家の崩壊まで続くだと？
But why?
しかし なぜだ
なぜ否定できない？
Why can't I say it's impossible?
何なのだ この違和感は…
What is this strange feeling I have?
それに―
Also, the feeling I get from
this logic and writing...
このロジックや論文全体から
受ける印象は どこかで…
I recognize it!
#3 Krueger Street, Zolka Cafeteria
My grades and school reputation
are progressing nicely.
（ターニャ）
学内の成績と評価は上々
And I have connections in operations.
参謀本部とのコネもあるし―
卒業後の不安材料は
限りなくゼロに近いな
There are next to zero concerns
about my life after graduation.
Captain Üger?
（ターニャ）ウーガ大尉殿
（ウーガ）あ…
It's rare to see you here.
珍しい所でお会いしました
A rifle and a paper.
（ウーガ）ライフルに新聞
相変わらずだな
You're the same as ever, huh?
The ideal soldier.
まさに 軍人の鑑(かがみ)だ
（ターニャ）
そういう大尉殿こそ―
What about you?
軍大学の誉れである
“12騎士”のランクは確実だと
I heard you're certain to be one of
the Twelve Knights, the school's pride.
Is there something wrong, Captain?
大尉殿 何か？
First Lieutenant Degurechaff,
this may be rude to ask,
デグレチャフ中尉
失礼なことを聞くが
but why did you volunteer for the military?
なぜ 君は軍に志願した？
With your talents,
you could have done anything.
君ほどの才幹があれば
道は いくつもあるだろう
So why?
なぜ わざわざ…
My father was a soldier.
私の父は 軍人でした
"Was"?
“でした”ということは…
Then...
（ターニャ）母にも捨てられ
孤児となった私には―
My mother abandoned me,
and I became an orphan.
There was nothing for me to do
but join the military.
軍隊以外の道など
ありませんでした
But... I don't know how to say this...
しかし なんと言っていいか
分からないが―
君は まだ子供だ
軍人は辞めるべきだ
You're still a child.
You should leave the military.
Do you doubt my capabilities, Captain?
大尉殿は小官の資質を
疑われるのですか？
No!
それは違う！ 違うが…
I don't, but...
I have a kid now.
子供が生まれた 女の子だ
A girl.
それは… おめでとうございます
Oh, wow.
Congratulations.
When I look at you,
（ウーガ）
中尉を見ていると ふと思うのだ
I ask myself if my own daughter
will have to go to war.
自分の娘も戦争に行くことに
なるのだろうか… とな
Sending cute little kids to
the battlefield is insane.
かわいい盛りの子供を
戦場に送るなど どうかしている
Don't you think so?
そうは思わないか？
Captain, you're a nice person.
大尉殿 あなたは優しい方だ
You're rational, and you have a conscience.
理性的で 何より良識がある
But...
そんな…
But that's why you should get to the rear
before the madness truly begins.
でも だからこそ
狂気の幕が開ける前に
後方に下がるべきです
それは 許されない行為だ
I... can't do that.
Captain, you need to fight battles to live.
大尉殿 生きることも戦いなのです
So that your daughter isn't
sent to the battlefield, too.
娘さんを戦場へ送らないためにも
Want to have lunch?
（ターニャ）
よろしければ 昼食にしませんか
The wurst here is quite good.
ここのブルストは なかなかですよ
No, sorry, but I'll be going.
いや すまないが これで失礼する
My wife's waiting for me at home.
家人が待っているものでね
Captain Üger has now dropped out
of the promotion track,
（ターニャ）これでウーガ大尉は
出世コースから脱落
and I have a guy with a conscience,
who knows the battlefield, on my side.
なおかつ 戦場を知る良識人を
味方につけたわけだ
“精神的に無防備になった相手を
説得すべき”
You should try persuasion when
people are mentally defenseless.
The fascist who proposed that
was a demonic genius.
そう主張したファシストは
悪魔的天才だな フフッ
Imperial Strategic Headquarters, Conference Room 1
The redeployment of our central
forces to the Rhine front
（座長）
現在 ライン戦線は―
中央本隊の
再配置により―
小康状態を
保っている… と
has caused a lull in the battle.
ですが 西方方面軍が
崩壊寸前になったのも事実
But it's also true that the forces in the
western theater were nearly destroyed.
It's critical that we reorganize
and reinforce them.
防衛戦力の増強と再編が
急務でしょう
（参謀長）とは言え 現状での
大規模な軍管区再編は困難だ
But doing a large-scale military
reorganization now will be difficult.
I'm well aware.
それは重々 承知しております
そこで 他の案を提言したいと
And so, I want to suggest something else.
Do you have a plan?
何か妙案が？
The creation of a new rapid-response force.
新たな即応軍の創設です
（参謀）それでは遊兵を
つくってしまうのではないか
But that would create a force we aren't using.
Operations needs a highly mobile force
that we can move at will.
作戦局としても 機動性を持った
任意に使える戦力が必要です
Is this the "Plan for a
Rapid-Response Mage Battalion"
数日前 貴官が
中心となって提出した
that you and your people
submitted a few days ago?
“即応魔導大隊構想”か
はい 大隊規模なら
引き抜きに差し障りはなく
Indeed.
A single battalion isn't a major loss,
and it can be quickly deployed.
展開力も高いと
（参謀長）
構想自体は理解できるが…
I understand the plan, but...
（ゼートゥーア）既に優秀な人材も
確保しております
I have the ideal person in mind.
戦功はもとより
提出させた論文が―
They have combat experience,
and the paper they submitted speaks
of exceptional vision and judgment.
卓越した視野と判断力を
物語っておりました
Imperial Army Western Theater Garrison
Is that set in stone?
（レルゲン）
それは決定事項なのか？
Yes.
（連絡係）はっ 昨今の情勢です
Given our situation, they said we can't
let talented soldiers sit idly by.
有能な軍人を
遊ばせる余裕などないと
Did they read the report I submitted to them
about her time at the officer academy?
小官が両閣下へ提出した
士官学校時代の報告は
確認いただいたのか？
Yes. But it seems they've decided
she's grown at the military academy.
はい ですが 軍大学で成長したと
判断されたようです
（レルゲン）成長？
Grown?
A person's true nature
doesn't change that easily!
人間の本性は
そう簡単に変わるものではない
Is that why they wanted me to read this?
これを読めとは そういうわけか！
Imperial Strategic Headquarters, Dining Room
Once again, thank you so much
for inviting me today.
（ターニャ）改めて
本日はご招待いただき―
誠に
ありがとうございます
I'm amazed you've became one of
the Twelve Knights at your age.
（コードル）その年で 12騎士の
ランクに選抜されるとは―
まったく驚きですな
ゼートゥーア閣下
Aren't you, Zettour?
Yes, it's amazing.
ああ 見事なものだ
Your words honor me.
（ターニャ）
過分なお言葉 恐れ入ります
You're still growing, right?
（コードル）
育ち盛りだろう 遠慮は無用だ
Eat all you want.
（ターニャ）
はい 満喫させていただきます
Yes, I plan to.
How do you like the dish
Strategic HQ is known for?
（コードル）
どうだね？ 参謀本部の名物は
On the front lines, you don't
really eat steamed food, but...
（ターニャ）前線では あまり
口にできない蒸し料理だが―
正直 海軍のガンルームで
とる食事のほうがマシだろうな
Truthfully, I'd probably be better off
eating in a naval armory.
（ターニャ）
は… 素直に申し上げるならば―
To be honest, it reminds me
a lot of the front lines.
前線を思い出す見事なものだと
ほーう すばらしい回答だ
That's a splendid answer.
いっそ“常在戦場の食堂”とでも
名付けてみようか
Perhaps we'll call it the
"Cafeteria of the Unending Battlefield."
Now, let's get to the point.
（コードル）
さて そろそろ本題に入ろう
I'm sure you know this,
分かっているとは思うが―
来てもらったのは
貴官の卒業後の配属についてだ
but we've asked you here to discuss
your post-graduation deployment.
（ターニャ）
どれも本国の安全な部隊勤務
These are all safe stations
within the Empire.
And after two years of experience,
２年ほど経験を積めば
参謀将校本流への仲間入りか
I can join Strategic HQ, huh?
In light of your past exploits,
（コードル）貴官の武功を考慮し
人事局は選択に口を挟まない
Personnel will not intervene
in your selection.
好きに選ぶとよい
Pick whichever you like.
I have lots of good choices, don't I?
より取り見取りですね
迷ってしまいます
I'm not sure.
What's this?
これは？
実は 参謀本部からも１通ある
There's actually another one
from Strategic HQ.
I'll be on my way.
さて 小官はこれにて
幸運を祈るよ デグレチャフ君
Good luck, Degurechaff.
Yes, sir. Thank you, Colonel.
（ターニャ）あっ はい 大佐殿
Thank you, Colonel.
大佐 ご苦労であった
（ターニャ）人事の書類は建前
The stuff from Personnel was just for show.
I never had a choice.
初めから選択肢などなかった
（ゼートゥーア）貴官のことだ
実務的な話のほうが よかろう
Knowing you, I'm sure you'd prefer
we get right down to business.
First Lieutenant Degurechaff,
デグレチャフ中尉 貴官には
I intend to put you in charge of
a new rapid-response mage battalion.
新設の即応魔導大隊を
任せるつもりだ
A battalion?!
大隊… で ありますか？
だ… 大隊が適切でしょう
I... I believe a battalion
would be sufficient.
（ターニャ）あ… あの時か！
Was that it?!
Leading a rapid-response battalion is
a bigger risk than the front lines!
即応大隊を率いるなど
前線以上のリスク！
Due to its rapid-response nature,
it would answer directly to Strategic HQ.
大隊は即応の観点から
参謀本部直轄
基本的に 貴官の上官はいない
Essentially, you would have
no superior officer.
し… しかし 小官は中尉です
B-But I'm only a first lieutenant.
大隊を率いるのには
適切ではないと…
I'm not qualified to command a battalion.
（ゼートゥーア）心配は要らん
すぐに編成官の辞令を入れる
Don't worry. I'll put in an order to
make you an organizer immediately.
編成官？
An organizer?
The position of organizer has
been obsolete for a long time,
（ゼートゥーア）
もはや形骸化して久しい職務だが
制度上は利用できる
but it's still available.
When you graduate, you'll be promoted
to captain and become an organizer.
卒業と同時に
編成官として大尉へ昇進
And, once you've "organized" the battalion,
その後 大隊編成の功で
無理やり少佐にねじ込む段取りだ
we'll reward you by forcing through
a promotion to major.
I have all the preparations ready.
全て手はずは整えた
That's a very enticing offer.
まさに 我が世の春ですね
Why?
（ターニャ）どうして…
どうして こうなった!?
Why did this happen?
So, how much time do I have to organize it?
それで 編成の期限は？
The sooner, the better.
（ゼートゥーア）
早いに越したことはない
Pick up to forty-eight
people of your choosing.
48名以下なら 好きに編成したまえ
Roger.
了解しました
では 小官は これで…
I'll be going, then.
Lieutenant...
（ゼートゥーア）中尉…
I'm told that you can be
very difficult to work with.
貴官は
人を選びすぎるとも聞く
I don't question your ability,
but you have a bad reputation.
能力を疑うわけではないが
あまりよい風評ではない
Keep that in mind.
留意しておけ
Thank you for your warning.
ご高配 感謝いたします
Good luck!
武運を祈る！
Sending a kid to war, huh?
（ゼートゥーア）
子供を戦争に送る… か
Damn it!
（ターニャ）
クソッ！ こうなったら
少しでも選抜に時間をかけ―
I'll have to take as much time as possible
with the selection process
and delay our shipping out.
出動の機会を
引き延ばすほかあるまい
Imperial Strategic HQ External Bureau
（ターニャ）
何だ これは…
Organizer Section
What is this?
募集して まだ１週間だぞ
I only sent out that
recruitment notice last week!
Mages are the elite, aren't they?
魔導師はエリートだろ？
普通なら好待遇を望むはず
Shouldn't they want the
best jobs they can get?
I made it clear in the notice
that this would be a terrible job...
なのに どう見ても
ブラックな求人広告…
"Mages Wanted.
"Extremely Difficult Battle, Little Pay."
"Spend your days in
"combat and unfathomable danger.
"If you return alive, you'll receive honor and glory."
"Spend your days in
"combat and unfathomable danger.
"If you return alive, you'll receive honor and glory."
こんな地獄の片道ツアーに
なぜ応募する？
Why would all these people sign up
for a one-way ticket to hell?
だいたい
１人で決裁できる量ではないぞ
I can't go through all this
stuff by myself, anyway.
It's impossible... Absolutely impossible!
無理だ ぜ～ったいに無理だ
Okay.
よし 人手不足を理由に
時間稼ぎを…
I'll use the lack of personnel
as an excuse to buy time.
Excuse me.
（女性）失礼します！
What are you doing here?
貴官が なぜここに!?
It's been a while, Captain Degurechaff!
（ヴィーシャ）お久しぶりです
デグレチャフ大尉殿
This is...
This program is fiction.
All persons, groups, places, laws,
and names appearing in it have
no relation to the real world.
Next Episode
My First Battalion
good stuff...
（ゼートゥーア）
これは… いい品だな